PERSONAL INFORMATION

Claudia Panait



Bucharest (Romania)

+40723655419

panaitclaudia84@gmail.com

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I desire to develop my career, while following my passion for technology, business and people. I would like to take all oportunities to use my 12 years experience in IT sales, together with my excellent communication and planning skills. Building up teams and leading the members to effectively achieve both their personal and professional objective have always been the highlight of my professional mission.

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/07/2011-31/12/2019

SALES MANAGER

SC Power Net Consulting SRL, Bucharest (Romania)

- elaborating, proposing and implementing the company's sales plan, accompanied by a dynamic policy of continuous increase in the volume of sales;
- planning clear objectives for the orientation and organization of the sales activity in the company;
- coordinating and guiding the way of organizing and carrying out the activity of the Sales Agents, to ensure the efficient use of the working time;
- coordinating the Sales and Presales team of the company in order to streamline the work processes between them and to achieve quarterly / annual targets;
- leading the assigned customer projects: creating the project plan; driving project execution while considering the optimisation of costs and resources in the time schedule;
- coordinating the implementation of the won projects, both for the public and the private sector and managing multiple subteams: sales, presales and technical;
- recruiting, training and developing the sales team, in collaboration with the Human Resources Department;
- running weekly meetings with each of the team members to check the project's status and their approach to the clients;
- planning and monitoring the team's projects: Organizing and managing all phases of the projects to ensure on-time and on-budget completion; Identifying the work to be done; Defining and guaranteeing the project schedule; Tracking costs / financial reporting / invoices;
- maintaining and developing relationships with the company's main software and hardware partners: IBM, Dell, Microsoft, VMware, Forcepoint, Oracle, CA Technologies, Cisco, Fortinet;
- developing strategies and organizing promotional campaigns for new products / services: direct marketing campaign, organizing events;
- representing the company within the Romanian-British Chamber of Commerce
- implementing the company's ISO certifications: ISO 9001, ISO 18001, ISO 27001, ISO 20000;
- analyzing market trends and proposing new development directions and new solutions and services in the company;
- identifying and contacting potential customers in order to submit the offer, negotiate, conclude and execute the commercial contracts;
- drafting weekly reports to the management regarding the situation of sales and receipts, proposing methods for their improvement and growth;
- verifying of signed contracts both legally and procedurally.



Accomplishments

- I increased the company's sales to existing customers by 20%, once the implementation of the Dynamics CRM system was finished;
- I increased the number of clients in the private sector by 50%;
- I supported my team in presenting new ideas and forecasts, working close to its members in order to develop a healthy relationship and a friendly work environment;
- I negotiated and concluded new strategic partnerships for the company with vendors such as Forcepoint, Cososys;
- I accomplished the quarterly and annual targets / department;
- I successfully coordinated the implementation of the company's Dynamics CRM system;
- I coordinated the implementation of the company's website;
- I implemented the marketing strategy in order to increase the company's online visibility: Social Media Marketing, Email Marketing, Website Development & SEO; AdWords campaign;
- I was part of the team responsible for the due diligence process for obtaining external financing within the company.

31/05/2009-31/07/2011

Sales Project Manager

SC Power Net Consulting SRL, Bucharest (Romania)

- Accountable for managing the delivery of critical projects and for providing managerial support for all the projects conducted by the company;
- Organizing and managing all phases of the projects to ensure on-time and on-budget completion; Identifying the work to be done; Defining and guaranteeing the project schedule; Tracking costs / financial reporting / invoices;
- Creating and managing the project plan; Coordinating/Managing the relation with Business and with the Supplier;
- Coordinating/managing contracting activities;
- Planning and managing, in collaboration with technical team leaders, the allocation of resources to projects;
- Handling the usual variation of the workload by using the external partners resources;
- Keepping Top Management and all Stakeholders constantly updated on the progress, challenges, risks of the project and secure the support needed to achieve goals. Completing required project documentation and updating repositories;
- Responsible for client progress meetings, cost control, invoicing, variation claims, invoice payment resolution and conditions of contract;
- Organising and facilitating Project Steering / Operating Committees meetings;
- Managing the internal team in delivering the proposals to the customers;
- Reviewing and approving all project documentation;
- Escalating issues and areas of concern to senior managers;
- Ensuring staff and subcontractor's timesheets were accurately completed;

01/10/2006-30/05/2009

ACCOUNT MANAGER

SC Power Net Consulting SRL, Bucharest (Romania)

- representing the company in the relationships with clients from the managed segment: both public and private sectors;
- selling IT equipment and software products (promoting, bidding, negotiation, signing the contract) from the company's portfolio;
- submitting commercial offers and qualification documents in public tender procedures;
- coordinating the submission of final offers in public tenders;
- working on commercial and technical offers in collaboration with the technical department and presenting these offers to the clients;

Curriculum vitae Claudia Panait

- continuous market prospecting within the distributed segment for finding new customers;
- managing the allocated accounts and increasing the volume of sales in all these accounts;
- managing the execution of the contracts signed with the clients: contract signing, products orders, implementation, follow-up;
- managing the relationship with the internal distributors for the products that the company offers to its customers (requesting offers, negotiating, placing orders and tracking deliveries);

Accomplishments:

- I exceeded the target by up to 50% for the clients in the public sector;
- I increased by 70% the number of offers submitted for the public auctions;
- I improved the working process with the Presales department within the company;

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

01/10/2007-15/06/2009

Master Degree in Project-Based Business Management

Academy of Economic Studies, Bucharest (Romania)

01/10/2003-15/06/2007

Bachelor Degree in Cybernetics, Statistics and Economic Informatics

Academy of Economic Studies, Bucharest (Romania)

15/09/1999-15/06/2003

Baccalaureat Diploma

National College Mihai Viteazul, Bucharest (Romania)

PERSONAL SKILLS

Foreign language(s)

English French

UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
C2	C2	C1	C1	C1
A1	A1	A1	A1	A1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user - B1 and B2: Independent user - C1 and C2: Proficient user Common European Framework of Reference for Languages

Communication skills

- Good comunication and negotiation skills gained through my experience as a Sales Manager;
- Excellent interpersonal skills, including negotiations and problem resolution in cross functional team;

Organisational / managerial skills

- Demonstrated experience of priority setting and delegation skills;
- Sound organizing and planning skills to oversee and successfully implement program deliverables;
- Experienced in project planning, resources planning, risk analysis and organization;
- Advanced Project Management skills including strong reporting, planning, communication and organizational skills;
- Strong time management, leadership and problem solving skills;
- Execution and management of multiple teams;
- Ability to follow instructions;
- Self motivated, positive and proactive "can do" attitude;
- Ability to take ownership of the project and successfully solve unexpected issues with a minor





impact;

- Understanding the importance of customer service, confidentiality, quality and security;
- Capacity to work as a team member as well as independently;
- Willingness to improve and learn and support other team members as well;
- Strong Excell Skills;
- Sound knowledge of systems and processes: ERP, CRM, BI

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Courses

- Agile SCRUM Course- SCRUM Fundamentals
- Prince 2 Foundation Course;
- Project Management Essentials (PMP I) Course;
- Project Management Office Setup Guide Course;
- Microsoft Project Course;
- "Outword Mindset" Workshop for Top Leaders- Jim Ferrell Arbinger Institute
- "GKTI Semper Human Management" course held by Silviu Hotaran
- Leadership Horse Eye Seminar
- Excel advanced Course
- "Super Sales Secrets" ACCELERA Course
- Sales Courses ACCELERA 4X4
- Negotiating Techniques ACCELERA Course
- Sales Academy CNDV Course

Certifications

- Prince 2 Foundation Certification 2019;
- Excel Advanced Certification:
- HP Sales Training- HPE2-E55 Introduction to Selling HPE Products, Solutions and Service;
- Forcepoint- Inside Sales Certification;
- VMware- Sales Professional;
- Dell- Sales Specialist;
- CA Technologies Infrastructure Software Products -Sales Certification;
- Microsoft- Sales and Marketing Competency Assesment for private Cloud, Management and Virtualisation;